<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>random on Beyrak's Blog</title><link>https://beyrakin.github.io/tags/random/</link><description>Recent content in random on Beyrak's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 02:36:23 +0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://beyrakin.github.io/tags/random/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>[AZ] ISO 27001 nədir?</title><link>https://beyrakin.github.io/posts/iso27001-az/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 02:36:23 +0400</pubDate><guid>https://beyrakin.github.io/posts/iso27001-az/</guid><description>ISO 27001 nədir? ISO 27001 İnformasiya Təhlükəsizliyi İdarəetmə Sistemi (ISMS) üçün tələbləri müəyyən edən beynəlxalq standartdır. ISMS, təşkilatın informasiya risklərinin idarə edilməsi proseslərində iştirak edən bütün hüquqi, fiziki və texniki nəzarətləri özündə cəmləşdirən siyasət və prosedurlar çərçivəsidir.
ISO 27001-in məzmunu ISO 27001 10 hissəyə bölünür:
Giriş Əhatə dairəsi Terminlər və təriflər Təşkilatın konteksti Rəhbərlik Planlaşdırma Dəstək Əməliyyat Performansın qiymətləndirilməsi Təkmilləşdirmə Giriş ISO 27001-in tətbiqi standart və onun məqsədi haqqında ümumi məlumat verir.</description></item><item><title>[En] What is ISO 27001?</title><link>https://beyrakin.github.io/posts/iso27001-en/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 21:51:47 +0400</pubDate><guid>https://beyrakin.github.io/posts/iso27001-en/</guid><description>What is ISO 27001? ISO 27001 is an international standard that specifies requirements for an information security management system (ISMS). An ISMS is a framework of policies and procedures that includes all legal, physical and technical controls involved in an organization’s information risk management processes.
Contents of ISO 27001 ISO 27001 is divided into 10 parts:
Introduction Scope Terms and definitions Context of the organization Leadership Planning Support Operation Performance evaluation Improvement Introduction The introduction of ISO 27001 provides an overview of the standard and its purpose.</description></item><item><title>Who am I?</title><link>https://beyrakin.github.io/posts/about-me/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 09:53:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://beyrakin.github.io/posts/about-me/</guid><description>Who am I? “Cyber-Security is much more than a matter of IT.” - Stephane Nappo
Hi👋, I&amp;rsquo;m Beyrak, and I am a CS student. (CS looks so cool both as a Computer Science and as a Cyber security :D)
Interests Red Team, Threat Intelligence Golang, C/C++, etc. Linux Social https://www.linkedin.com/in/beyrak/ https://github.com/beyrakIn https://tryhackme.com/p/beyraklnc https://beyrak.me/ ba@beyrak.me</description></item></channel></rss>